## **Sophie King**

23 Old School Drive, Wheathampstead, Hertfordshire, AL4 8FH
Mobile (07833231932)
Email (sophiek89@hotmail.com)

## PERSONAL PROFILE/CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am an outgoing and hardworking person. I can think on my feet and I am motivated by challenge. I am extremely apt at transferring the skills that I have learnt during my education and across a variety of sectors into new projects. For example, I endeavoured to use my philosophy degree in my teaching and set up an after school enrichment club, as well as running a group for pupils who needed extra support with their debating and analytical skills. Before leaving the financial sector I was undertaking the Investment Management Certificate as well as shadowing analysts throughout the research report process. I have also sought support from supervisory analysts to learn how to create and use financial models. I have excellent mathematical skills, having completed an A-Level in the subject, as well as developing my knowledge of mathematics in order to teach it successfully. A key skill that I learnt during my degree was to analyse information and arguments and to find solutions to problems. I can handle data effectively, which I believe would enable me to thrive in an analytical role. I work well on my own, but also flourish as part of a team and I build positive, professional relationships in the work place.

## **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

January 2015 Fitch Learning: Introduction to the Global Financial Markets

Sept – Dec 2014 Quest Professional, London Graduate

**Training Programme:** 

**Business, Marketing and Secretarial Skills** 

Touch Typing, MS Office 2010

Diary Management, Travel Arrangements, Expenses and Business Correspondence Marketing, Practical Advertising and Management, Introduction to Business, Finance and the Economy, Business Law, Current Affairs, Sales and Negotiation, Event Management

Level 3 Award in Effective Management from the Institute of Leadership & Management

## **EDUCATION**

Sept 2012 – July 2013 2008 – July 2011 Sept 2003 – June 2008 University of Hertfordshire University of Nottingham Haileybury College, Hertford

Post Graduate Certificate of Education Philosophy BA (2:1)

**A2-Levels:** Religious Studies (B), Mathematic(B), Psychology (B) **AS-Levels:** Chemistry (C)

GCSEs: 11 GCSEs Grades A\*-C

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

July 2016 - Present

# King's K9s and Cats Business Owner

- Sourcing and maintaining clients
- Marketing the business using social media, as well as creating websites and flyers
- Maintaining constant communication with clients
- Ensuring to keep up to date with good practice, such as undertaking a canine first aid course
- Keeping a detailed log of profit and loss
- Invoicing clients

## January 2016 - October 2016

## Edison Investment Research Research Assistant

- · Taking and distributing minutes for weekly Healthcare team meetings
- Maintaining publications schedule for the team and communicating this with relevant members of the company and Head of Research
- · Scheduling meetings between clients, non-clients and analysts, especially when clients are reporting results
- Co-ordinating team members attendance at conferences and events
- Identify relevant newsworthy research to give to Edison's PR
- · Writing and updating client monthly book profiles to reflect recent news flow and share price movements

- Managing and developing parts of the monthly book, such as the client Catalyst Calendar and recording the top and bottom performers
- · Writing descriptive company summaries for research reports and conference profiles
- Supporting analysts with research reports by compiling and cross referencing data from BioCentury with other sources
- Producing tear sheets on clients and non-clients ahead of conferences

## Dec 2014 - January 2016 Edison Investment Research

#### **Production Assistant**

- Responsible for creating conference books. Most recently the Deutsches Eigenkapitalforum, consisting of 175
  company profiles. Main tasks: managing analysts' reports, collating the PDF, pricing up the reports, formatting, light
  editing
- Uploading notices to the relevant platforms, such as Bloomberg and BlueMatrix
- Pricing up financial reports, ensuring any price sensitive information is up to date in the text and calculating any price sensitive ratios
- First point of contact for analyst formatting queries
- Uploading the most recent models to our internal systems
- Co-producing Edison Monthly Insight. Editing and collating profiles on over 200 of our clients each month into a PDF document
- Managing the distribution of research reports according to urgency and location
- Coordinating project work alongside the Project manger
- Ad hoc administrative tasks
- Ensuring branding and house style is consistent by providing full training to new starters and existing analysts in the use of the departmental template

# Sept 2013 – July 2014 St Albans High School for Girls Teacher (Year 1)

- Responsible for teaching 20 Year 1 pupils in all National Curriculum subjects, including Maths, English and Science
- Management of two Teaching Assistants
- Organising trips on behalf of the school in line with learning requirements
- Attending and contributing to regular staff meetings, as well as meeting with the Head to discuss important issues such as child protection
- Contributing to curriculum evenings. Each year group teacher would prepare a presentation about a particular subject, for example in Multiplication and Division and present to any parents that wished to attend. This was to show the progression across the year groups, from Reception to Year 6
- Consistently used regular summative assessment of the pupils to inform future teaching
- Responsible for data handling of summative and formative assessment, which I had to input into the school system
- Meeting with parents for regular updates on progress, as well as termly parent's evenings
- End of year reports that reported on the entire year's progress

# June 2011 –Sept 2012 Private Households (Various) Nanny

- During this time I was a nanny for several families where the parents were working professionals
- Responsible for collecting the children from school and taking them home as well as preparing meals
- Liaising with parents to ensure a link between school and home. I was responsible for highlighting any issues or letters/messages from the school and alerting the parents to this
- Calendar management. I arranged play dates, activities and special summer plans
- Driving the children to extra curricular activities, such as swimming, ballet and music lessons

# June 2012 St Albans High School for Girls School receptionist (supply)

This position was for two weeks in June. This experience enhanced my administrative skills and gave me a good insight into the front facing aspect to the school. The duties within this role included:

- Arranging the 'New Pupil' folders
- Manning the main school telephone
- Responsible for the registers and following up any late or absent pupils
- Selecting the calls which went through to the Headmistress
- Greeting the pupils off the coaches and ensuring they were safe arriving to school
- Linking younger pupils with younger pupils to walk up to the school

Summers of 2005, 2009–2011 Various Catering Companies Front of House

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

2005

2012 Child and Infant massage Certificate to aid children with gross motor difficulties Volunteer Classroom support at St Albans High School for Girls

June 2011 – July 2012

Sept 2010 (2 weeks) Work Experience at Haslingfield Endowed Primary School as classroom support 2009

I provided a telephone service as a qualified Nightline trainee

2006 2 weeks work experience shadowing different employees at Travers Smith law firm

During my Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Award I help the local community with recycling and co-

created a termly magazine.

Gold gymnastics B.A.G.A certificate

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Pole fitness – I have been learning pole for 3.5 years and have performed in several **Interests** 

showcases

Music - Grade 5 Saxophone, Grade 5 Piano

Reading – I used my own love of reading to inspire the pupils in my class

Baking – In my free time I love to bake

Animals – I support several animal charities and keep up to date with animal rights

Full, clean UK Driving Licence

**Computing Skills** Extremely competent in advanced MS Office, internet research presentations and SMART

Mac and PC user

References available upon request